

# Dan Oprita

### IT SPECIALIST

# Summary

I have more than 7 years of experience in the IT filed, providing technical support for various applications and dealing with several technologies and customers. The main field of work was on Product Data Management using specific software but I have also been in touch with technologies like Linux, Java, Oracle SQL. At this point in time I'm focused on learning web development so I'm attending specific courses (HTML&CSS, JavaScript, Angular) and developing websites (for myself and for friends).

#### Area of interest:

- JavaScript / Angular
- Web development
- Software development
- · Object oriented programming
- · Agile / Scrum

# **Experience area:**

- · Software technical support
- · Linux administration
- Product Lifecycle Management
- Siemens Teamcenter
- Catia 3D design

#### CONTACT:

BRASOV +40 726 168 721 dan.oprita88@gmail.com www.danoprita.ro

### **Work Experience**

# **2017 - PRESENT: TEAMCENTER Technical Support**IBM

- Administration, maintenance, troubleshooting and incident resolution, in cooperation with the Client or 3rd party suppliers
- Updating application settings and configuration on the application servers
- Plan, coordinate and assist the technical implementation of new application versions in the Test and Production Environments
- Maintain and update descriptions for security and backup/restore procedures for the applications

# 2015 - 2017: APPLICATION Technical Support IBM

- Deploying and replicating new application releases from reference location to all Linux servers of the customer plants
- Updating application settings and paths on code servers
- Various configurations and maintenance of the CAD server environment
- · Building application packages to be installed on the servers

# **2011 - 2015: CATIA/ENOVIA Technical Support** IBM

- User support on Catia V5, Enovia LCA & client specific applications
- Testing of custom build application (CAD data integration)
- Responsible for various service requests (involving platform settings changes, support level 3 issues, addressing Catia bugs to Dassault Systemes

## **Education & Training**

2010 - 2012: Master of Mechanical Engineering — Automotive Transportation

TRANSILVANIA UNIVERSITY

2009 - 2010: Erasmus scholarship — Mechanical Engineering

KARLSRUHE INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY - KARLSRUHE, GERMANY

2006 - 2010: Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering - Automotive Transportation

TRANSILVANIA UNIVERSITY

### **SKILLS**

- Linux and Windows server administration
- CAD 3D design, Catia V5 software
- ITIL processes
- JBoss, Webserver
- Product Lifecycle Management methodology
- · Application testing, requirement engineering
- Java/Swing, Agile, OOP
- JavaScript, HTML&CSS, Bootstrap

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Front End Development (HTML, CSS, JS)
- Catia V5 Part Design specialist
- Catia V5 Assembly Design specialist
- ITIL V3 Foundation

# **COURSES**

### Personal training:

- JavaScript / HTML / CSS attended an 100h classroom certified course
- Angular 4 current self learning

### Internal company training:

- Java / Swing classroom course
- Linux foundation classroom
- Siemens Teamcenter
- Webserver (Tomcat, WebSphere)

### **CONTACT:**

BRASOV +40 726 168 721 dan.oprita88@gmail.com www.danoprita.ro